Guide to the William Henderson Woolverton Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
William Henderson Woolverton papers
1912-1994
MS 1748
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
0.5
The collection consists of correspondence, clippings, photographs, and genealogical material, primarily documenting the World War I service of William H. Woolverton. The papers also include personal papers and materials relating to the Woolverton family.
Woolverton, William Henderson
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of John F. Woolverton, 1999.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Biographical / Historical
William H. Woolverton was born in 1891 in New York City. He attended Phillips Academy in Andover, Massachusetts and Yale University, where he attained a B.A. in economics in 1913. After graduation, Woolverton joined the United States Army. He participated in the First World War in France, Italy, and Germany as a member of the Army Ambulance Corps. He returned to the United States in 1919 where he worked as an officer in the New York Transfer Company. In 1928, he moved to his family's estate in Alexandria, Pennsylvania, where he managed two large farms. In 1942, Woolverton was commissioned again into the army. He served at the Staten Island Port of Embarkation for two years, before going to England as part of the Transportation Corps and later to Germany as part of the army of occupation. In 1945, he was discharged with the final rank of major, and he returned to Pennsylvania, where he lived the rest of his life. He married Frances Curtis Woolverton in 1917. Woolverton died in 1969.
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of correspondence, clippings, photographs, and genealogical material, primarily documenting the World War I service of William H. Woolverton. The papers also include personal papers and materials relating to the Woolverton family.
World War, 1914-1918; Woolverton, John Frederick, 1926-; Woolverton, William Henderson; United States. Army -- Amubulances; United States. Army ( Military life); United States. Army. Ambulance Corps, 90th
- Inventory, 1912-1994
  Scope and Contents
  The series is arranged alphabetically. Correspondence with Woolverton's wife, Frances Curtis Woolverton includes a detailed inventory created by John F. Woolverton for the first two folders of letters.
  Other materials documenting the Woolverton family can be found at the Huntingdon County Historical Society (Huntingdon, PA) and the Bishop Payne Library (Alexandria, VA).
  - Biographical material [prepared by John F. Woolverton], 1994, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Clippings [re: William H. Woolverton's wedding to Frances Curtis Woolverton], 1917 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence
    - Cone, Ethel Woolverton [sister], 1945 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Woolverton, Anna [aunt], 1912 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Woolverton, Frances Curtis [wife]
      - Inventory of correspondence [prepared by John F. Woolverton], undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
      - Letters, 1917-1919 (Box 1, Folder 6-8)
  - Genealogical material, 1994, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Photographs, 1912-1940s, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - World War I
    - Correspondence, 1914-1917 (Box 1, Folder 11-12)
    - Scrapbook, 1915-1919 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - United States Army Ambulance Corps
      - Company log, 1917-1918 (Box 1, Folder 14-15)
      - 1928 reunion (Box 1, Folder 16)